Ka Wai (Karry) Wong, Ph.D.

Burlingame, CA 94010 • (530) 574 3799

ucdwong@ucdavis.edu • LinkedIn • Google Scholar • GitHub

Professional Profile -

Versatile and collaborative software engineer utilizing 3 years in tech and research to deliver impactful algorithm and data structure solutions in 3D geometry and computer vision used in Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality (AR/VR). Applied math PhD, avid coder, and multilingual professional in software engineering.

Core Proficiencies

Programming Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB

Languages: English, German, Mandarin (fluent), Cantonese (native), and Hebrew (conversational)

Professional Experience -

Meta Reality Labs • Burlingame, CA

Visiting Researcher

Jun. 2022 - Present

- Develop computer vision algorithms focused on large-scale 3D reconstruction and mapping, accurate
 user localization, and structure from motion together with bundle adjustment, to support functionality and
 enhance performance of AR/VR devices for such as <u>Oculus Quest</u> and <u>Ray-Ban Stories</u>
- Conduct experiment to identify false positives in map alignment, developing rejection mechanism to resolve merge errors and ensure maps of different physical spaces are not combined inadvertently.
- Build benchmarking system to profile different components of on-cloud map merging pipeline

Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory • Livermore, CA

Postdoctoral Researcher

Oct. 2021 - Jun. 2022

- Achieved first-ever 3D temperature measurement of nuclear fusion hotspot via <u>computed tomography</u> and <u>3D geometry modeling</u> by developing noise-robust 3D reconstruction algorithms (MATLAB)
- Enabled data-driven and machine learning analysis (Bayesian inference, Markov-Chain Monte-Carlo) on experimental data using Python libraries <u>emcee</u> and <u>large simulation dataset</u>

Graduate Student Researcher

Dec. 2019 - Jun. 2021

• Earned 2x higher accuracy in x-ray emission measurement of nuclear fusion experiments by developing image denoising algorithms to analyze 100+ 2D x-ray images, featured in 3-min SLAM video

Autodesk • San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer Intern

Jun. 2021 - Sept. 2021

- Developed stochastic algorithm to compute volume enclosed by lattice structures for 3D printing
- Solved various 3D computational geometry problems involving implicit modeling, B-rep, and NURBS

Rohde & Schwarz USA • Beaverton, OR

Software Engineer Intern

Jul. 2019 - Sept. 2019

• Fixed 10+ critical bugs in object-oriented programming codebase (Python/C++, 3000+ lines) by implementing automated unit tests in WiFi technology (various WLAN 802.11 standards)

Software Testing Engineer (Munich, Germany)

Apr. 2016 – Sept. 2016

Designed and developed automated unit test cases for Wideband Callbox on 4G LTE

Center for Educational Effectiveness, University of California, Davis • Davis, CA

Graduate Student Researcher

Summers 2017/18/19

 Recipient of <u>Outstanding Graduate Student Teaching Award</u> out of 2,000+ teaching assistants, in recognition of outstanding communication for classes in calculus and advanced math topics

Education -

Ph.D. Applied Math • University of California, Davis • Davis, CA • Sept. 2021 • GPA 3.9

M.Sc. Math • Technical University of Munich • Munich, Germany • Sept. 2015

Visiting researcher • Hebrew University of Jerusalem • Jerusalem, Israel • Sept. 2014 – Jun. 2015

Academic exchange • Technion • Haifa, Israel • Sept. 2012 – Sept. 2013

B.Sc. Math • 1st class honors • Hong Kong University of Science and Technology • Hong Kong • Jun. 2011